Özer Özdal

Contact Information

Tel: +1 438 935 74 64 ozerozdal@gmail.com linkedin://ozerozdal github://oozdal iNSPIRE: O.Ozdal.1

Personal Information

•Date of birth 28/05/1990 •Place of birth Izmir, Turkey

Languages

Native Turkish Advanced English French (A2 Level)

Software Skills

Monte Carlo Sampling
Statistical Modeling
Linear regression
Clustering
Quantitative Analysis
Data Visualization

Coursework

•Machine Learning
•Deep Learning
Specialization
•SQL for Data Science
•Linear Algebra
•Multivariate Calculus
•Probability Theory
•Computational Physics
•Classical Mechanics
•Quantum Mechanics
•Statistical Mechanics

Tools

PYTHON, C++ SQL, FORTRAN CERN ROOT, LaTeX Bash shell scripting MATHEMATICA. MATLAB

Packages

Scikit-Learn, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Pytorch, TensorFlow

Data Science Experience

since 2018 **Machine Learning in High-Energy Physics** Concordia University My goal is to compare two D dimensional samples: the SM simulated events (background to BSM searches), and the real data, and to check if the two are drawn from the same probability density distribution.

Education

2016-2020

	Phenomenology of new physics beyond the Standard Model: signals of dark matter and new gauge bosons at colliders. Lead to five scientific publications.	
2016–2017	Inter-University Transfer Student Took two graduate courses: Quantum Field Theory I - II	
2014–2016	M.Sc. in Theoretical High Energy Physics Izmir Institute of Technology The Higgs boson and right-handed neutrinos in supersymmetric models. Lead to two scientific publications.	
2009–2014	B.Sc. in Physics (Ranked 3rd) Izmir Institute of Technology Revisited N-symmetric barrier tunneling in Quantum Mechanics	

Concordia University

Concordia University

Ph.D. in Theoretical High Energy Physics

Experience

2020-

2016–2020	Research Assistant (RA) Mariana Frank Research Grou	Concordia University
2019-2020	Visiting Ph.D. Student Supported by MITACS Globalia publications.	NExT Institute & University of Southampton nk Research Award. Lead to two scientific
2016-2020	Teaching Assistant (TA) TAed for 8 physics courses. Conflice hours and tutorial session	Concordia University Graded assignments and wrote solutions, lead ons.
2015–2016	Research Assistant (RA) Studied muon anomalous magnetic moment and yukawa quasi-unification in supersymmetric Models. Lead to two scientific publications.	
2012–2012	Internship	Koç University, Mechanical Characterization Lab

Relevant Accomplishments

Postdoctoral Researcher

- 7 peer-reviewed scientific publications in High Energy Physics
- · Gave 17 talks about my research at conferences
- Awarded Globalink Research Award by MITACS and Graduate Student Mobility Award

Created vibration modeling in nanowire resonators with mechanical coupling

- · Attended 18 scientific workshops, summer/winter schools in top institutions
- · B.Sc. in Physics 3rd Ranked Award